- 越狱前情提要  - 我们找到迈克尔了
- Previously on Prison Break... - We found Michael.
我没想到还能见到这张面孔
Never thought I'd see this face again.
你本来不应该见到的
You weren't supposed to.
你属于我  斯科菲尔德  不管你在计划什么
I own you, Scofield. If you're planning something,
我总会先你一步
I'll always be a step ahead of you.
你的丈夫
Your husband.
雅各布就是波塞冬
Jacob is Poseidon.
他是为CIA探员
He's a CIA operative,
潜伏得很深
deep cover.
他负责一个名叫21空室的分裂机构
He runs a splinter cell called 21-Void.
他因为我的技能选中了我
He targeted me for my skills.
四年前  他背叛了我从而占有你
Four years ago, he betrayed me so he could have you.
- 他是怎么背叛你的  - 我们当时
- How did he betray you? - We were meeting a man
见了一位叫哈兰・盖因斯的人
named Harlan Gaines,
他是中情局的副局长
a deputy director of the CIA.
那天晚上波塞冬射杀了盖因斯
Poseidon shot and killed Gaines that night.
我知道自己被下了套
I knew I was being set up.
迈克尔  现在他和我们的儿子在一起
Michael, he's with our son right now.
斯科菲尔德在寻找同伴  梳理监狱人员
Scofield was looking for a partner, combing prisons,
想找一个能够应付他的人
looking for someone who could handle himself.
你想跟我说什么
What are you trying to tell me?
这些在你身上根深蒂固  你是从我这里继承的  儿砸
It was ingrained in you, son. You got it from me.
通过屏幕抓取获得了他通过网络电话从沙漠传送出来的图像
Screen grab of the Skype transmission he sent from the desert.
有那么多中加密的方式  为什么选择这个
Of all things to encrypt, why that?
这件事结束后我就与21空室毫无瓜葛
I'm done with 21-Void after this.
加入了21空室就没有退出这一说 范
There's no leaving 21-Void, Van.
不妨把嘴闭上  把钱给我  博罗斯
How about you just shut up and pay me, Burrows?
我没钱
I don't have it.
你知道我是谁吗
You know who I am?
我会帮你和你妈妈逃出去的
I'm gonna get you and your mother out of here.
我们得快点离开了
We need to run.
六分钟前
你知道你是个精神变态者吗
Do you know that you're a psychopath?
我向你保证  我绝不是唯一一个向自己的家人
I assure you, I'm not the first CIA man to hide his life
隐藏自己生活的中情局人员
from his family.
你向中情局掩盖了其存在
You hid it from the CIA.
听着  如果你想搞砸一件事
Look, you want to screw something up?
那就让一堆人去搞  你想成事
Put a thousand people on it. You want to get it done right?
交给几个人去负责  我们所做的一切
Put it in the hands of a few. What we were doing
是为了推动这个国家的进步
was advancing this country's cause.
释放像 阿布・拉玛尔这样的人
How does freeing a man like Abu Ramal
怎么能推动国家的进步
advance this country's cause?
这个并不能
Well, it doesn't.
之前的任务
The missions before,
都是为了这个国家的利益着想  但是
they were for the good of the country, but...
这个任务不是为了国家
No, this one wasn't about country.
这是为了你
It was about you.
没人想要孤独终老  萨拉
Nobody wants to die to their old life, Sara.
迈克尔也不想
And Michael didn't.
他孤注一掷地想要留在你身边
He wanted to hold on to it so desperately.
在那一刻  我想要
In that moment, I wanted him
让他走开
to go away,
整个协议
the whole agreement,
都只是为了占有你
and just have you.
你把他派到也门去送死
You sent him to Yemen to die.
我不断说服我自己将是我所说的最后一个谎言
Kept telling myself this was gonna be my last lie.
一切都会随着时间的流逝  我们婚礼的举行
That it would fade with time as we had anniversaries,
以及抚养孩子的过程慢慢褪去
raised that beautiful child.
那不是你的孩子
That is not your child.
是我把他养大的
I raised him.
这份感情是真的
That love is real.
这不是个谎言
It's not a lie.
你把他当作诱饵
You are using him as bait.
你这个人渣
You son of a bitch.
她知道不能伤到他
She knows not to hurt him.
你是如此痴迷于解决迈克尔
You were so obsessed with Michael
以致于你要拿我的儿子去冒险
that you would risk my son!
迈克尔  你是在说你吧
Michael? You mean you.
你并不爱我  那都是你的自负在作祟
You don't love me. Your ego's too big.
你忙着成为房间里最聪明的人怎么会有心思管我
You're too busy trying to be the smartest man in the room.
然后你遇到了我的丈夫
And then you met my husband,
然后你意识到
and you realized
他比你聪明
he's smarter than you.
我不这么认为
I don't think so.
你确定吗
You sure?
我确定
I'm positive.
我们之间的感情是真的  萨拉
Our love was real, Sara.
那都是过去式了
Past tense.
我还爱着你
I still love you.
一切准备就绪  老板
Everything's set, boss.
很好
Good.
不得不夸奖你
Got to give you credit.
不辞辛劳地为一个人
You'll go the whole nine yards to help one man
窃取另一个人的妻子
steal another man's wife.
不  不  不  别和她说话
No, no, no. Don't talk to him.
否则会怎样  他还能
Or what? He'll do something
对我做些什么  你反正要杀了我
you're not already gonna do? You're going to kill me.
不管你之前说了多少次我爱你
No matter how many times you tell me you love me first.
闭嘴
Shut up!
迈克尔没有杀哈兰・盖因斯  他没有动机
Michael didn't kill Harlan Gaines. He had no motive.
- 闭嘴  - 他才是那个有动机的人
- Shut up. - He's the one with the motive.
哈兰・盖因斯是你的长官
Harlan Gaines was your CIA director
他之前在调查雅各布
and he was looking into Jacob.
他想要把雅各布关起来
He was gonna put him prison.
该死
Damn it!
把她的嘴用胶带封上
Tape her mouth shut, please.
封死
Tape it shut.
如果你这么做了  一个无辜的人会死
If you do, an innocent man dies,
而真凶会逍遥法外
and the real killer walks.
你还不明白吗
Don't you understand?
是雅各布杀了哈兰・盖因斯
Jacob killed Harlan Gaines.
闭嘴
Just shut it.
有什么问题吗
Is there a problem?
他来了  是时候了
Here he comes. It's time to do this.
十分钟后这个地方会被烧毁
This place is gonna burn down in ten minutes.
如果能给你点慰藉的话
And if it's any solace,
我可以告诉你我们的儿子不是其中之一
our son won't be one of them.
山中无老虎  猴子称大王
While the cat's away, the mice will play.
事情不太对劲
Something's wrong.
我得到了你的地图
I got your map.
我会把你和妈妈救出去的
I'm gonna get you and your mother out of here.
地图不是我画的
I didn't draw a map.
我们得快点走了
We need to run.
等一下
Wait.
你上来做什么  范
What are you doing up here, Van?
我只是想确定我们抓对人了
I just want to make sure that we're getting the right guy.
问他几个问题
Ask him some questions.
放我儿子走
Let my son go.
我任你们处置
Do whatever you want with me.
放我儿子走
Just let my son go.
命令里没有包括问问题
Orders weren't to ask questions.
命令是当场击毙
It was to shoot on sight.
也许我们应该问问题
Maybe we should ask questions, damn it.
如果斯科菲尔德杀了哈兰・盖因斯
If Scofield killed Harlan Gaines,
如果有必要的话  我们带他去警局
we take him to the police, if we have to.
我们通过合法的途径来处理
We get this done the right way.
波塞冬不会放过我们的
Poseidon would never let us live.
他不会找到我们的
He won't find us.
我跟你说  如果我们想消失  没人能找得到
I told you. We want to disappear, we disappear.
我可以做到
I can make that happen.
我把他交给警察
We turn him in,
我们就可以远走高飞
and we're gone.
别逼我这样做抉择
Don't make me choose like this.
艾米莉
Emily.
这真的有的选吗
Is it really even a choice?
不
No.
因为没有退出21空室这一说
'Cause there's no leaving 21-Void.
快走
Go.
你的叔叔就在车道尽头
Your uncle's at the end of the driveway.
别回头  快跑  快
Don't turn around. Run! Go!
萨拉
Sara.
我们的孩子呢
Where's our boy?
林肯叔叔  林肯叔叔
Uncle Lincoln, Uncle Lincoln!
- 不  不  不  是我  - 出什么事了
- No, no, no, it's me. - What's going on?
他们在开枪  我好害怕
They're shooting. I'm scared.
- 好的  他们想要抓你  - 谁
- Okay. They've come for you. - Who?
我不会让他们伤害你的
I am not gonna let them hurt you,
你们明白吗  快上车
you understand? Get in the car.
不  我们现在得走了  小迈  该走了
No, we've got to go now, Mike. We've got to go.
那妈妈怎么办
What about my mom?
先进去  快
Go, go, go.
小迈  不要
Mike! No!
不
No!
别走
小迈
Mike!
他抢走了他
He took him.
- 萨拉  - 他抢走了我们儿子
- Sara... - He took our son.
别去了  我们回去  宝贝
Come back to me. Come back to me, sweetheart.
到我这来
Come back to me.
我们得集中注意力  好吗
We got to stay focused, all right?
这事没完  不会这么快解决的
This is not over. Not by a long shot.
- 林肯呢  - 什么
- Where's Linc? - What?
我们得找到林肯
We got to find Linc, okay?
先找林肯
We're gonna find Linc.
林肯
Linc.
我的天
Oh my God.
林肯  林肯
Linc. Linc.
我让你失望了  迈克尔
I let you down, Michael.
我本来有机会就该除掉卢卡的
I should have taken care of Luca when I had the chance.
你没让我失望  你也预料不到
You didn't let me down. You couldn't have known.
因为你我们才能差点救回小迈  林肯
We're so close because of you, Linc.
你把我带回了家
You got me home.
是你
医生给他打了镇定剂  迈克尔
They've stabilized him, Michael.
我们帮不上忙
There's nothing we can do.
我得带你尽快离开这里
We've got to get you out of here right now.
你得给我些指示什么的
Okay, you got to give me some direction here, you know?
一些
Some, um...
父亲的建议
fatherly advice
教教我如何处理和你这样的父亲的
on how to deal with having a father that's, um...
关系
you.
就是
Well, you know, uh...
这事对于你我来说都不容易接受
Is this blood freaking you out like it's freaking me out?
是的
Yeah, yeah. Let me, uh...
斯考菲尔德说父子关系能拯救你我
Scofield said that it would deliver me. Both of us.
我只需要
All I have to do
给他父爱
is just get it to him.
就可以理解了
I understand why.
现在我终于明白了
So I can finally understand this.
他给了你这个
He give you this?
执你之手
"By your hand, you shall know
共享天棱之乐
the glories of your progeny..."
那  那是
I-It's, it's...
天伦之乐  傻孩子
It's "progeny," dear boy.
天伦之乐
"Progeny.
我们的世界将永远回归正途
And our world will be made right forevermore."
一开始  我以为这和宗教有关
Originally, I thought it was a religious thing.
上帝之子什么的
You know, son of God, and all that.
但现在我知道
But now I know it's...
是指我的儿子
it's my own progeny.
你
You.
确实是天伦之乐
It's a glorious thing indeed.
即使我他妈不知道如何处理父子关系
Even if I don't have a damn clue how to deal with it.
你我彼此彼此
You and me both.
我有一个找回
I've got a way to get
我们儿子的办法  萨拉
our son back, Sara.
我从雅各布一开始让我离开
I've been planning to bring Jacob down
你和小迈开始就计划打倒他
ever since he forced me to turn my back on you and Mike.
因为我一直被关在也门监狱
A plan I had to put on hold
所以计划未能执行
while I was in that Yemeni prison.
我必须等到逃出来才能施行
I had to wait till I got out.
直到所有所有事情归位
Till everything aligned.
直到现在
Till now.
请告诉我你们找到线索了
Tell me you got something.
它在抗拒我
It's eluding me.
眼睛纹身的代码比我编的更强大
There's an even bigger code encrypted into the eyes.
你读出了什么
And what's it say?
我还不知道
I don't know yet.
但是以我使用的处理技术
But with the amount of processing power I throw at it,
很快我们就会找出答案了
we're gonna find out real soon.
怎么了
What's wrong?
我  我不知道怎么和你说
I-I don't know how to say it, so, um...
刚才那个人是个警察
That man was a police detective,
他告诉我你妈
and he told me your moth...
你妈妈死了
your mother's dead.
什么
What?
我知道  别难过
I know. I know.
但我会带你到安全的地方
But I'm gonna take you somewhere safe,
这样那些坏人就
where those people that are trying to hurt you
害不到你了
can't reach you.
为什么他们要害我
Why would they try and hurt me?
因为我爱你
It's because I love you.
他们想以此来让我难过
And they're trying to hurt me...
夺走我唯一所爱
Take the one thing that I truly love away.
为什么他么要伤害你
Why would they try and hurt you?
因为有些关于我的事情
Because there are some things
我还没和你说
I haven't told you about me.
我给你发那封信是有原因的
I sent that letter to you for a reason.
波塞冬在监控我与每一个
Poseidon was monitoring my communications
潜在的线人  或者同伴
with everyone who could possibly be a resource
之间的通讯  却并不监控我和
or an ally, but not with people
讨厌的人的联系
I despised.
你就直说吧  你到底怎么想我的
Give it to me straight... How you really feel about me?
我想如果我对一个
I figured if I showed grace to a man
从未受过恩会的人做点好事
who'd never seen it before in his life,
他也许会很感激
maybe he'd be grateful,
愿意帮我们一把
do something for us.
帮我们所有人
All of us,
包括他自己
himself included.
我们的生活将永远重回正轨
"And our lives shall be made right forevermore."
我的意思是普通的  日常生活
I'm talking about normal, everyday life.
得到我们大家很久很久没有体会过的哪种自由
The kind of freedom none of us has known in a long, long time.
但波塞冬不会轻易放过我们
But Poseidon's not just gonna let us go.
他紧紧控制了
He's got me and your son
我和你儿子
in an iron grip.
必须有人让他放手
Someone has to make him let go.
你明白了吗
Do you understand?
我跟上你的思路了
I'm tracking where you're going.
我们能回归那种
Only way we're gonna get
你口中说的
that beautiful, mundane life
美好又平凡的生活的唯一办法
you're talking... Any of us...
就是我取了他的性命
Is if I take his.
从现在开始我们就安全了
We'll be safe here for now.
听着
Hey, listen,
我承诺过会向你解释的
I promised I'd explain.
那些人追杀我的原因是
The reason those people are after me...
我知道很难让你相信
I know this is gonna be hard to believe,
但我差不多是个特工
but I'm basically a secret agent.
进来
Come on in.
你还记得你在后院里的堡垒吗
You know that fort you've got in the backyard?
来到一个更大的堡垒感觉不错吧
It feels good to go somewhere like that, right?
一个无人知道的地方  没人能伤到你
A place no one knows about, where no one can get to you.
这就是我的安全堡垒
Well, that's what this place is for me.
没事的
It's okay.
别害怕
你可以出示
Would you please show him
你的证件吗  布莱克特工
your credentials, Agent Blake?
艾米丽・布莱克特工  CIA
Agent Emily Blake, CIA.
关于你家门口发生的悲剧
I'm sorry that had to happen
我感到很抱歉
in front of you at the house.
她被派去监视我们家保护你
She was stationed at the house to protect you...
让你免受那个最终会出现
from exactly the man who ended up coming,
自称是你父亲
the man who said
的人的伤害
he was your dad.
真的吗
Really?
这些年我为了保护美国树了不少敌人
I've made enemies defending America over the years.
最糟糕的是
Worst part is that this
这个坏人又激起了你对你父亲的会议
particular one dredged up the memory of your father.
事实上  小迈
The truth is, Mikey,
不管你如何想  你父亲七年前就
despite what you may want to believe, your father died
死了
seven years ago.
喂
Yeah.
我是迈克尔・斯考菲尔德
This is Michael Scofield.
我们正在谈论你
We were just talking about you.
我给你最后一个拯救自己的机会
I'm giving you one last chance to save your life.
把我儿子还给我  否则我不保证接下来
Hand the boy over or I can't be held responsible
你会承受什么后果
for what happens next.
你是在威胁我吗
Are you threatening my life?
我说的只是你不照做的下场
Only if you don't hand him over.
我绝不会把我的儿子交给你
I'd never hand over my son.
他从来就不是你的儿子
He's not your son and never was.
离我爸爸远点
Stay away from my dad,
你听见了吗
you hear?
走开
Stay away!
好孩子
Good boy.
他喊他爸爸
He called him Dad.
雅各布
Jacob.
不  他只是给他洗脑了而已
No, he's-he's brainwashing him, that's all.
你说得对  像那样的人
Man like that, you're right.
他应该去死
He deserves to die.
他在哪里
Where is he?
波塞冬在哪
Where is Poseidon?
会有人处理他的
He'll be dealt with.
等一下  等一下
Wait, hang on, hang on, hang on, man.
如果你被捕了
If you get caught...
如果他被抓了  他就得回到监狱里去
If he gets caught, he's going back to the pen.
- 来吧  - 我不能
- Come on, come on. - I'm not...
如果我不那么做呢
And if I don't do it?
老天  我只是想让你干干净净的
Criminy, I want you free and clear,
如果只有一条路能实现我的目标
and if that's the only way to do it,
那我一定会义无反顾的那么做
then I got to be the one that does it.
斯科菲尔德就不会那么做
Scofield ain't gonna do it.
他没有杀戮基因
He don't got the killing gene.
没有人会被抓住
No one is getting caught.
我有我的特殊计划
There's a very specific order to this.
萨拉  我需要你确保
Sara, I want you to make sure
林肯的安全  让他不要受伤
Linc's safe and out of harm's way.
鞭子和T-bag  你们负责给我们提供一张王牌
Whip, T-Bag, you're gonna collect a wild card for us.
一个雅各布所不了解的东西
One that Jacob doesn't know is out there.
我得先去个地方  这一切开始的地方
I'm gonna go to the nest, where this all started,
藏匿秘密的地方
where the secrets lay hidden,
血泪终将流淌在属于它们的地方
and where blood will finally be spilled in its rightful place.
我刚才从斯科菲尔德那里接到一通电话
The call I just got from Scofield...
我想知道是从哪打来的
I want to know where it came from.
定位数据
Location data
马上发送给你
coming to you right now.
不知道是什么地方
Middle of nowhere.
向东北方向移动  并且挂断电话
Started moving northeast and the phone was shut off.
或者扔了
Maybe tossed.
你和那个该死的动物园  斯科菲尔德
You and your damn zoo, Scofield.
我会全部弄清楚
I'm gonna find out once and for all
你到底在那里搞什么鬼
what you were really doing there.
你到底在计划着什么
What you were really planning.
然后我会亲手杀了你
And then I'm gonna kill you.
我了解你的所有
I know everything about you.
甚至是你平庸的举措
Even your most mundane actions.
就像这个动物园  到底隐藏着你的什么秘密
Like the zoo. What's with you and the zoo?
我要了解这个人所有的细节
I had to know everything about the man
那个把计划刻在皮肤上的人
who wore his plans on his skin.
一目了然
In plain sight, yet
却如此神秘莫测
so mysterious.
通向绝对的权力只有一条道路
The secret to real power
就是永远不要背叛你的信仰
is to never betray your intentions.
隐藏自己的外在
To wear nothing on your sleeve,
收敛自己的内心
and to never let anyone see your face.
我永远会在你前面一步
I'll always be a step ahead of you.
我可以从你眼中读懂一切
I can see everything in your eyes.
什么
What?
我从你的眼神解谜
I decrypted the code from the eyes.
这是拿破仑的一句名言
It's a quote from Napoleon.
什么名言
What quote?
当你的敌人在犯错的时候
"Never interrupt your enemy
千万不要打断他
when he's making a mistake."
这是那双眼睛里所隐藏的信息
It's what's behind the eyes that counts.
想必你已经知道我正站在你关闭的服务器前面
Thought you should know I'm looking at your closed servers right now.
我手上捏着你的硬盘驱动
I'm holding your hard drives in my hand.
你所有的秘密通讯
All your secret communications.
足够让你一辈子消失了
Enough to send you away forever.
恭喜你  迈克尔
Bravo, Michael.
不管怎么说  恭喜你进到那里面去了
However you got in there, bravo.
你把我引导动物园来  所以你能进到我的办公室
You sent me to the zoo so you could get into
但是你我都知道  你的威胁外强中干
my office. But you and I both know your threat's a hollow one,
因为你知道我手上也有筹码
because you know I've got something
比你的价值更高  你的儿子
that's even more valuable to you: your son.
我们又回到博弈论当中去了
So we're back to game theory.
我们何不谈一个协议
Do we work together, make a trade
让彼此双方从中获利呢
so we both get what we want?
或者你想试试谁的招数更阴吗
Or are you gonna try something underhanded?
你知道我会同意的
You know I will.
我也会  所以我们何不
As will I. So why don't we
忘记过去  实现双赢
cut past that and make a deal?
当然了  迈克尔
Sure, Michael. Yeah,
我们就这么办
let's do that.
老船厂
Old shipyard.
A仓库
Warehouse A.
明天下午五点见
5:00 p.m. tomorrow.
好的
Fine.
打扰一下
Uh, excuse me?
我丈夫的哥哥  林肯・巴罗斯
My brother-in-law... did-did Lincoln Burrows,
他换病房了吗
did he get moved?
没有女士  他自己出院了
No, ma'am. He checked himself out.
- 他流了很多血  - 我知道
- He was down a lot of blood. - I know.
我们试过阻止他  但是如果患者坚持这么做
We tried to stop him, but if a patient insists,
这在他的权利范围之内  我们也没办法
if it's within their power, we have to let 'em go.
这是巴拉德医生
Uh, this is Dr. Ballard.
- 是他做的手术  - 你好
- He did the surgery. - Hi,
萨拉・斯科菲尔德  实际上我之前在伊萨卡岛是个内科医生
Sara Scofield, I'm an internist, actually, up at Ithaca.
你知道他有可能会去哪里吗
Do you have any idea where my brother-in-law might have gone?
- 不太清楚  - 好吧
- No idea. - Right.
在手指湖发生了什么事
What happened up in Finger Lakes,
你知道吗  另一个枪击案的幸存者
do you know? Another gunshot victim
同一区域 同一时间
came in from the same area
送到我们这里来了
at the same time.
我大伯只是个例  肯定是巧合
My brother-in-law was alone. It must be a coincidence.
但还是谢谢你
But thank you.
我要走了  我已经尽力了
Well, I'm heading out. I've done what I can.
他现在靠三级救助方案在硬撑
He's on life support up on three,
但是坦白讲  我不觉得他能撑到早晨了
but candidly, I don't think he's making it till morning.
卢卡
Luca.
你让我着实逃了一阵子
You had me running there for a bit,
一直在想我是哪里做错了
thinking I'd done something wrong.
你确实错了  你骗了我10万美元
You did. You stiffed me $100 grand.
不  那是脏钱
Nah. It's blood money.
脏钱不能还债
No debts with blood money.
告诉我我们扯平了
Say we're clear.
做梦吧  巴罗斯
Eat me, Burrows.
告诉我扯平了
Say we're clear.
我会带更多人来的
I'm gonna get more guys.
你就继续亡命天涯吧
And you'll be running again.
这次不会
Not this time.
又是你那帮假朋友吗
Are those your fake friends again?
你个王八蛋
You son of a bitch.
这次不是
No. This time,
这次是真的
they're real.
联邦探员
Federal agents!
把手举到我能看到的地方
Hands where I can see 'em!
- 举起手来  - 巴罗斯
- Hands up! - Burrows!
举起手来
Do it now!
巴罗斯
Burrows!
我需要你的帮助
I need your help.
我要找到我的儿子
I need to find my boy.
在这里
Here.
他是一个恶人  抢走了我的儿子
He's an evil man and he's got my son.
你一定认识什么人
You've got to know someone.
知道什么东西
Something.
一些能把我的儿子抢回来的路子
Some way I can get my boy back.
拜托了
Please.
你确定我儿子在这里吗
You sure this is where my son is?
谢谢你
Thank you.
好了
It's all right.
杀戮是不对的
Killing ain't right.
是的  我也读过圣经
Yeah, I read the Bible.
你确定
You did?
你知道吗  我曾经在旅馆房间内扫过一眼
You know, I scanned it once in a hotel room.
你打算怎么做
Well, what you gonna do?
别杀任何人  除非他们真该死
Don't kill anybody unless they really deserve it.
没错  你肯定读过旧约全书了
Yeah, you must've read the Old Testament part.
以眼还眼  以牙还牙
An eye for an eye, a tooth for a tooth.
当然了
Sure, whatever.
我就是说说
Yeah, I'm just saying,
有时  王  王八羔子
sometimes, certain... Certain sons of bitches,
需要根除一下他们的旧思想
they just need to be plain old eradicated.
最好让他们在世界上消失
World's just better minus them.
像阿布・拉马尔
Like Abu Ramal.
但最重要的  杀戮是件坏事
But for the most part, you know, killing's just bad.
没错
Yeah, absolutely.
除了波塞冬
Except Poseidon.
- 没错  他是该消失了  - 该消失了
- Yeah, he's got to go, too. - Got to go.
我只是不想你
I just don't want you to get the wrong idea
- 误会我  好吗  - 好
- about me, okay? - Okay.
你得像瑜珈信徒那般看待它  好吗
You got to see it like the yogis, okay?
去其糟粕  取其精华
Destroying the negative to create the positive.
像跳湿婆之舞那样
The dance of the Shivas and all that.
拂去黑暗  让光明重现
Murder the dark, so the... The light can be born.
你要疯狂起来了  是吗
You're out of your damn tree, aren't you?
- 真懂事  - 棒
- Now you know where you got it from. - Great.
蓝色夏威夷在里面吗
Is there a BlueHawaii in there?
是  别磨蹭了  快进来
Yeah, don't just dillydally, come on in.
你美们这两个亡命之徒都是斯科菲尔德的人吗
I assume you two desperados are Scofield's guys.
没错
Yeah.
他也带你们越狱吗
He get you out of prison, too?
不是
No.
但我欠他人情
But I do owe him.
他从哪把你带出来的
Where'd he break you out of?
巴兰基亚市  南美洲
Barranquilla, South America.
像我这样柔弱的小男孩
They were gonna eat my lunch down there,
监狱里的人会把我午餐吃掉
pretty boy like me.
斯科菲尔德同情我
Scofield took pity.
我估计  他看到我身上有的天赋  就带我出来了
Saw a talent in me, I guess. Got me out.
作为回报  他说可能有一天会用上我
Said he might call on those talents some day in return,
所以我就在这了
and now here we are.
我尽快完成这个
Soon as I put the touches on this,
之后我就听你差遣  我一直等得好无聊呀
I'm yours. Got bored waiting.
这很厉害
It's incredible.
还原迪利广场
Rebuild of Dealey Plaza,
肯尼迪遇刺的地方
where JFK was shot.
这里
This here
是一个书库
is a book depository.
如此关注这些小细节
Attention to detail like that,
真是让人疯狂
drive a man crazy.
看看我  就是一个糟老头
Look at me. I'm a crap house loon.
极度需要把过去
Excessive need to bring the past
在我生命中好好回忆下
back to life.
让它鲜活起来
Make it real.
但是  现在回忆够了
But enough of that.
是时候大干一场了  我说得对吗
Time for the real dance to begin, am I right?
我们会带他回来的  好吗
We're going to get him back, okay?
我们让你的万能牌就位了
We got your wild card ready to go.
谢谢你
Thank you.
我才应该感谢你
Me that should be thanking you.
没有你  就没有今天的我
You brought me all this way.
是我们一起努力的成果
We did it together.
我们会一起并肩作战的
We'll be doing this together.
你给了我家的温暖
You gave me family.
我很感激你
Seriously, thank you.
说到家的话
Speaking of family...
我们走吧
Let's go.
别乱碰  好吗
Don't touch that, please.
现在还不是时候
It's not an option right now.
我的儿子现在在哪
Now where is my son?
你知道你问的问题  我是无论如何
You ask questions you know there isn't a chance in hell
都不会回答的
I'm gonna answer.
那我们接着这个游戏吧
So we're back to the game.
事实是  我们一直都在博弈着
The truth is, we never left.
你手上没有好牌
You're not holding the cards.
- 我才有  - 你有吗
- I am. - Are you?
全世界的执法部门都在找你
Every law agency in the world is looking for you.
你不像是处在有利位置的人
Doesn't sound like a position of power to me.
如果我被捕  服务器里的东西就会发布出去
If I get arrested, those servers will be released,
你做过的所有事  都会公诸于世
and everything you've done will be exposed.
我会找到那些资料  销毁它们
I'll find them. I'll destroy them.
像我说的
Like I said,
我才是拿着一手好牌的那个人
I'm holding the cards.
哇哦
Whoa!
真没想到
Didn't expect that.
这有失你的身份  迈克尔
It's beneath you, Michael.
放他走
Let him go!
我应该想到的
Now that, I expected.
谢谢
Thank you.
放下枪怎么样  美女
How about we drop it, lady?
你以为我没预料到这境况吗
You don't think I expected this?
我们可以一天都玩这个
We could do this all day.
剧情反转再反转
Play contingency after contingency.
但你真的想这样下去吗
But do you really want to do that?
不  大卫  该死
No! David. Dammit!
后退  否则我现在就杀了他
Back off, or I kill him right now.
这肯定是
And that must be
你最后一次的剧情反转了
the last of your contingencies.
感谢你上演的好戏  迈克尔
Thank you so much for showing me, Michael.
太棒了
Oh, yeah.
你该料到我联系了联邦调查局
You should also know I called the FBI.
小道消息说
An anonymous tip saying
科尼尔・奥提斯会出现在这个货仓
that Kaniel Outis would be at this warehouse.
确认安全  现正向第二指定点移动
Keep clear. Moving to second position.
听着
Okay,
他们已经进来了  没时间了
they're in the building. There's no more time.
交出硬盘来  否则我们开枪
The hard drives, or we'll start shooting
- 把你打成渣渣  - 把那男孩
- your pieces. - Hand over
交出来
the damn boy!
闭嘴
Shut up.
美女  你放下枪  转身离开
Lady, put the gun down, walk away,
因为我不会为接下来发生的一切负责
as I cannot be held accountable for what's about to happen.
- 他敢动  就开枪  - 我曾在酒吧打架时
- He moves, shoot him! - I killed a guy
杀了一个人  他当时在调戏我女友
in a bar fight once. He was taking yang to my girl.
- 一秒搞定  我眼都不眨  - 别说了
- Took me one second to do it. - Don't do it!
听他的  他是非常聪明的家伙
Listen to him. He's a very smart man.
我在说你  鞭子
I'm talking to you, Whip.
不值得你为此牺牲  这是我的事
It's not worth dying for. This is my fight!
这是我们的事  我们大费周章地
This is our fight. We've come too far to let this
来让这家伙得逞
son of a bitch win.
这不在我们计划中
This wasn't the plan!
你闭嘴
Don't do it!
王八羔子们就应该消失
Some sons of bitches just got to go!
我们只是做了该做的
We're the only ones who could do it.
- 我没说错吧  老爹  - 大卫
- Ain't that right, Pa? - David!
你就试试
Try me.
鞭子
Whip!
不
No!
- 鞭子  鞭子  - 不
- Whip. Whip. - No.
振作起来  鞭子
Come on. Whip.
事情不该是这样的
This wasn't the plan.
大卫  振作点
David, stay with me.
振作点  兔崽子  振作点
Stay with me, boy. Stay with me.
硬盘  交出来
The hard drives. Now.
我看着他  没事  让我来
I got him. It's okay, I got him.
没事的
All right.
在那边
It's that way.
冷静点  伙计
Keep it calm, boy.
- 保持冷静  - 如果他也想逞英雄的话
- Stay calm. - If he tries to play hero, too,
解决他
execute him.
大卫
David...
你竟敢开枪射他  你这个贱人
You shot him, you bitch.
他不应该挑衅我的
He shouldn't have tried me.
- 大卫  - 别动  举起手
- David... - Hands up! Freeze!
现在举起手  我们是联邦特工
Do it now! Federal agents!
我们是联邦特工
Federal agents!
举起来  让我看到你的手
Hands where I can see them!
我
I'm...
我没事  让我
I'm good. I got to s...
看看你的脸
see your face.
别动  举起手
Freeze! Get your hands up!
安息吧  兔崽子
Go easy, son.
我们接下来要做什么
How we doing?
嘿
Hey.
我比你做的好
Better than you.
哦  感谢上帝
Oh, thank God.
你还好吗
You okay?
哦
Oh.
向前走  在下一个吊窗那里
Up ahead, in the next bay.
我要接个电话
I'll take that call.
我们找到他了  小迈克  我们找到了我们的孩子
We got him, Michael. We got our boy.
是个好消息
Good news for you.
但现在你没有理由能给我我想要的
But now you've got no reason to give me what I want.
这对你来说是个坏消息
Which kind of makes it bad news for you.
联邦特工
Federal agents!
你这个狗娘养的
You son of a bitch.
这个小屋
The cabin.
盖恩斯的夹克
Gaines' jacket.
摄像头  用来拍我的照片
Camera, taking my picture.
空的手枪
Blanks.
你故意想要我把枪从你那里拿回来
You wanted me to take the gun from you back there.
你比我想象的厉害多了
You're better than I thought.
为我真正犯下的罪行重新定义
Re-framing me for the murder I actually committed.
你陷害我杀了那个人
The one you framed me for.
迈克  处理那个尸体
Michael, pick up the body,
让它看起来从未发生过
make it look like it never happened.
你是天才  真的
Genius, really.
但是没人会再次调查那个案件
But no one will ever go for it.
真理是你所告诉人们的一切
The truth is whatever you tell people it is.
是你教会我的
You taught me that.
哦  太糟糕了  联邦调查局会到这里来
Oh. Too bad the feds'll be here
两分钟之后  看见你
in two minutes, see your little
在这做小场景  就会知道这一切都是扯淡
diorama here, and know it's all bull.
除了这一切都不会在这里
Except none of this will be here.
我也不会在这里
And neither will I.
你这个混蛋
Bastard!
啊
Aah!
这是发生在七年前的事情
This is for the last seven years.
不许动  把你的手举起来
Freeze! Get your hands up!
都举起来
Put 'em up!
是他  他就是科尼尔・奥提斯
It's him! It's Kaniel Outis!
感谢上帝你们能来
Thank God you're here.
感谢上帝
Thank God!
Thank God.
感谢上帝
举起手
Hands up!
感谢上帝你们能及时赶来
Thank God you guys got here when you did,
我能说的就这些
that's all I can say.
我的意思是  他会
I mean, he would have...
我刚才差点就死了
I'd be dead right now.
听着  如果你们没有别的事的话  我想回家
Look, if it's okay with you guys, I'd like to go home,
整理一下自己  你可以想象得到
clean myself up a bit. As you can imagine,
这是漫长的一天
it's been a long day.
没问题
That's okay.
谢谢你
Thank you.
雅各・安东・内斯
Jacob Anton Ness?
我能帮你什么忙吗
Can I help you?
你因参与谋杀而被捕
You're under arrest for the participation in the murder
- 哈伦盖恩斯  - 如果你说的都是废话
- of Harlan Gaines. - If you're talking about that nonsense
- 在这里  - 我们现在讲的是关于血液的证据
- in there... - We're talking about blood evidence
在你的办公室被发现了
found in your office
在大学里的  一个办公室
at the university. An office
只有你可以进出的
only you have access to.
找到了哈伦盖恩斯的血液
Harlan Gaines' blood.
血液最后将会被洒在
And blood will finally
被洒在它应该在的地方
be spilled in its rightful place.
什么  怎么
What? How...
这些是从哈伦盖恩斯被杀当晚丢失的画面
These are the missing frames from the night of the killing.
被波塞冬剪掉了
The ones Poseidon edited out.
是的  那是我  我从来没有否认过
Yes, I was there. I've never denied it.
他强迫我
He forced me to...
所以他才能够陷害我
so he could frame me.
所以在你的衣物中发现了血迹
So the blood evidence found in your belongings
是因为他让你处理尸体时沾上的
was because he tasked you with disposing of the body.
对的
Correct.
并且随着额外的血液证据被披露
And with the revelation of the additional blood evidence
在他在大学的办公室里被发现
found in his office at the university,
这完全能支持你的理论  不是吗
it neatly supports your theory, doesn't it?
他在那里
That he was there.
他就是那个枪手
That he was the gunman.
我想我有一个问题要问你
I guess I would have one question for you.
我是中央情报局局长
I'm director of the CIA.
我能意识到这一点  这就是我给你发邮件的原因
I'm aware of that. That's why I sent you the e-mail
邮件里有直接的证据
with the evidence directly.
我的问题是
My question is...
你也会利用我吗
would you be manipulating me, too?
我该怎么做
How would I do that?
好吧
Well...
你看这个证据看得太仔细了
you look too closely at this evidence...
图片中的元数据  退化的血液证据
Metadata in the pictures, degraded blood evidence...
但你可能会发现一些问题
You might find some problems.
这取决于你要仔细观察的动机
Depends how motivated you are to look closely.
波塞冬杀了你的副局长
Poseidon killed your deputy director.
多年来  他一直是贵公司的一名癌症患者
He was a cancer inside your agency for years.
我给你们展示了他的真实面目
I've shown you his face!
现在  冷静下来
Now, calm down.
你应该知道我们有洛克先生的同谋
You should know that we have Mr. Ness' accomplice,
安德鲁・纳尔逊被拘留了
Andrew Nelson, in custody,
多亏了你的兄弟
thanks to your brother,
当我们看到你的电子邮件
Once we saw your e-mail,
我们正在审问他
we interrogated him.
他公开披露21无效的
He's fully disclosed 21-Void's
你策划谋杀哈伦・盖恩斯
conspiracy to frame you for the murder of Harlan Gaines
通过给你一个新的身份来隐藏你的真实身份
and bury your identity by giving you a new one:
科尼尔・奥提斯
Kaniel Outis.
这意味着什么呢
What does that mean?
意味着
It means...
你可以走了  斯科菲尔德先生
you're free to go, Mr. Scofield.
你不知道我等了多久
You don't know how long I've waited
才听到有人那样叫我
to hear someone call me that.
另一件事
One other thing.
聪明才智水准
The level of ingenuity
你显示了这一切
that you displayed with all of this...
我们可以利用这样的人
We could use a person like that.
我不是在找工作
I am not looking for a job.
是这样
Right.
你可以为我做一件事
There is one thing you can do for me.
你喜欢它吗
You liking it here?
它很奇怪
It's strange.
再次活下来
Being alive again.
不在逃亡了
Not running.
是的
Yeah.
我也一直在亡命天涯
I've been running, too.
我知道
I know.
你为什么叫她
Why'd you call her?
因为我知道你不会
Because I knew you wouldn't.
真正奇怪的是
What's really strange is...
关于实际工作的事情
things actually working out.
是的
Yeah.
我爱你
I love you.
我也爱你
I love you, too.
他更擅长让自己进入
He's better at getting himself into...
他的固执
He's stubborn.
嘿
Hey.
嘿  宝贝
Hey, babe.
嗯
Hmm.
不习惯男人微笑  过来到这里
Not used to guys smiling, coming in here.
是啊  只是不打算坚持太久
Yeah, just not planning on sticking around long,
没别的事了
that's all.
是的  对的
Yeah, right.
找到了一个不错的人
Have a good one.
不  不  不  不要
No. No, no, no, no, no, no,
不  不  不
no! No! No!
警卫  警卫
Guard! Guard!
旧约全书：是基督宗教的启示性经典文献
湿婆: 印度教三大神之一，毁灭之神
肯尼迪被从大楼五层楼上射出的子弹击中太阳穴而死
FBI通缉令
科尼尔・奥蒂斯
越狱   第五季   重置
第   九   集
电影淘淘
WWW.DYTTBD.COM
更多电影美剧尽在（电影淘淘 www.dyttbd.com）